um yeah so i i guess to anybody that
ends up watching this
i wanted to have a chat with jubilee um
about the idea of sovereignty
specifically
um having spent
a good amount of time the last couple of
weeks um actually digging into anarchy
and some of the the thoughts in there
and over time
in the game space i've come to realize
or suspect that
maybe even some of the sovereignty
discussions may come out of that space
because i see
overlap not that it necessarily has to
um and then uh i guess
going into anarchy which is something
that i think most of us are raised to
think is crazy talk
um and also uh
from game b type people knowing some
smart people were actually anarchists
um caused me to give it another look
and then come to the realization that
anarchy itself the actual theory and at
least the same people
that follow it um there is logic and
reason behind it
and i even have learned um that a lot of
what i've always been about i guess i've
always sort of fought
for some things that are essentially
anarchy in theory
i don't know if i'd call myself an
anarchist but um
yeah i think a lot of the stuff there's
some good ideals to at least have
in mind to aim towards that said i do
run into
uh some challenges uh depending on who
i guess the purists i run into but
that's the same as any
uh ideology who are hung up let's just
say
on any kind of power relationship or any
kind of hierarchy
which then gets me into a spot and i
think most people of well how could you
do anything because every relationship
has
some kind of dynamic which then led me
to
i think jubilee had told me in passing
on a call once that she was i believe in
honor kiss i think you do you identify
that way
jubilee or um yes and no i've had other
people label me as anarchism and much
like you
what's that happening enough i kind of
was like okay i'll look at it and
there's things i agree with and things i
don't agree with for sure
i find my i myself am very
anti-hierarchical
but not for the sake of it like
doesn't mean that you have to just be
like there's no hierarchy
it's more voluntary hierarchy like i
don't wanna position over me
that i didn't agree to be in a position
of authority over me
and very brief you know like i'll sue
chef for somebody else who's the main
chef
no problem i'll follow your orders but
not
perpetual slavery or not even under
government doctors and stuff like that
totally
i go with the no the gnome uh from
saying his name gnome
kromsky um chomsky yes
um you know that kind of unjustified
hierarchy so it's like you know having
the mind to hey
not having overloads just for the sake
of it which i think a lot of people
would probably be okay with except for
overlords um
that makes sense to me so i think it
creates that space to constantly have a
discussion
are like hey should i follow these
people and should i
actually be sitting in a position where
i'm dictating things maybe i need to
realize hey that time has passed let's
kind of go back down into the the group
um so i think that's a healthy
frame to kind of always have around um
yeah so i think i've always kind of
operated that way on my own naturally
um but you know i'm not triggered by the
fact that jubilee has control of the mic
because she runs this uh
this the stream cast so i am okay with a
little bit of those power you know it's
inevitably gonna happen
so i do get into some i've been on the
anarchy reddit
um for the past two weeks so it's been
an interesting test
of myself so but it's been good um
so what i really wanted to talk to
jubilee about though was the idea of
sovereignty um which i think i've
you know i have no issues with it um in
general
um but i think that's where i struggle
at times
i do find even sometimes maybe in the
game b space but i think more externally
i run into people that use it almost as
a bypass for any accountability and that
is something that i definitely
not just about sovereignty but um or you
know
the way we use it but i i realize that's
something i get triggered on
quite a bit on all of the kind of tough
issues
we go on is when somebody yeah it's
because i tend to i guess be a person
that uh is trying to be active and find
solutions you know i'll raise
problems but i raise them with the
effort of trying to find solutions
and i do have a strong expectation that
of myself to first be respectful of
other people
but i expect i want the same thing back
and i really struggle
i'll try to make the example first but
then i struggle with people who
get to use something like sovereignty or
another and the other in spiritual
communities another word i learned this
week was spiritual bypassing so
basically when people find a way to
never have accountability
um so yeah i wanted to explore that with
you and your thoughts and maybe even
referencing
the the call uh you helped me through
actually the guidance you gave me about
a month ago when i got into it a little
bit with uh
another fellow game b person that was
saying things that i definitely
did not agree with and found a little
bit ignorant and offensive
so um but you know you
i think that the point you had made to
me was you know you have to
you choose who you engage with um or how
you're gonna react
i don't remember exactly how it was
framed and it was valid
but it wasn't triggered by you per se
cause basically i trust that you would
have a
reasonable conversation with me but i do
struggle with that edge and it you know
even
from the way it seemed to me your
position would be okay well you can't
make somebody and i can understand that
in a way but
it almost if i can't have the
expectation
entering a space that both of us are
going to hold ourselves accountable
to respecting each other and trying to
see that good faith i guess rule omega
um to me i have a really hard time
wondering well how can i stick around
those spaces because
to me there's a point when i can't
choose like you know if i give so much
of myself and somebody can just crap all
over me
and the community allows that um
yeah like i know i can choose but at the
same time should i have to
in all circumstances so yeah i wanna
yeah what are your thoughts on
kind of where i'm going there right so
yeah even the word sovereignty triggers
me a lot
a lot of the time i had to look up i had
to look up a definition of it
and i don't think it matters what
google's definition is of it but what is
your definition of sovereignty
like what do you mean when you say
sovereignty yeah so i guess the way i
would have always looked at it before
is um like i hadn't used it or you know
in any kind of meaningful way until
getting into the game b i guess space
but
um you know definitely accountability um
independence but more in the sense of
you know i grew up in as we've talked
about you know the rural farming lands
of saskatchewan and it's a very pull
your bootstraps up you know
mentality so definitely a hard a lot of
pressure on you where basically no
matter what's happening to you
if everything's on your shoulders so you
almost don't even get to
point out your circumstances which isn't
healthy and i'm not advocating that but
definitely i come into things
first expecting and i'm okay with this
at least for myself
really pushing on myself hard is what
can i do what's in my control
and i actually have a hard time
accepting what's not in my control
because i'm worried that i'm giving a
cop out so i really push to extremes on
myself
as to am i missing something is there
something i should be doing better here
um so but i also don't necessarily
expect
that back from everybody else to that
degree because i actually think it's a
bit crazy if i
was to project it onto somebody else i
don't know you can expect things of
ourselves we won't have others but
um yeah i guess it's just you know if i
impact somebody and they're upset it
doesn't matter why they're upset
if i wouldn't have gotten upset or
whatever that they are
so to me respect is to listen learn and
at least show that i care
and i will change whatever's possible
for me to do
so that we can work together so i don't
know if that's a good definition but i
think it gives you a feel for
what i spin around in that idea yeah and
i think me
for me sovereignty is very tied with
self-sufficiency
and before having this conversation i
was like okay yeah i can see why that's
triggering for me because i feel like i
can't
be self-sufficient no matter what like
my health just doesn't allow me to be
self-sufficient but it does allow me to
be sovereign
and that like being able to tease those
two apart and being like okay i know i
can't garden
and like do the things i would need to
be able to look after myself and my
family all on my own
and yet i can work in a group to get
that done
and i can and i demand sovereignty over
my own life like i can't have anyone to
be
else have to have that position
and um i just feel like it needs to
mention that like i
although i yes of an anarchist basically
because the label was given to me
the one place where i'm like beautiful
beautiful
communist anarchy i'm an ancon yes but
but then whenever i'm
in the anarchist spaces especially the
and come versus end cap spaces
i'm like oh you people can't have
anarchism you guys can't even like
talk to it like it's the irony of like
the very people who want it or the
people who i think are least capable of
actually
being able to follow through on it in
any way
absolutely yeah um yeah there's a people
and i guess as you know anyways maybe
anybody watching will not but um you
know having done some experiments
having created a co-living startup of
the last four years and i guess didn't
realize it in a lot of ways
different grassroots type anarchist
ideas trying to really
create a business you know in the world
that we are
but try to create a way of doing it
where it wasn't
you know i tried to you know i was
trying to in a way
create pathways where it isn't the
business that i think a lot of people
um you know the character of capitalism
and
tech bros you know given that it had a
lot of tech tie-in trying to respect
those things this goes into a lot of
different stuff but
point being what i ran into is i really
should to me it was important hey if i
show up and i show that hey i'm not
gonna be normal and i will give and i
will
i will one of the rules i try to aim for
you know in my team when i did have
because everything kind of crashed but
um was nobody should have to
we should be i try to make sure that i'm
understanding the other person's
position i'm fighting for them before
they even feel they have to
so really trying to understand like what
what is their situation what might they
feel what would they normally
think is going on in this situation like
if there's a dynamic where
you know there's going to be a clash or
i have needs but they also have needs
that you know to make sure that i'm
pushing for my needs respecting as much
as possible
or understanding as much as possible
what needs
do they have and what would their
arguments be for them or
against having to compromise for mine
because i i know how horrible it is to
show up in a room
and have people that pretend that your
needs don't exist so i'm really
sensitive to that but i think that
that's a
that's how i showed up to a lot of
people and they tended to be
you know the community they tended to be
people that i guess some of them
probably come from the anarchist stuff
as i've started to research more i'm
recognizing where some of the
ideas i ran into must have been rooted
at least some
at some times um you know post-modernism
gets in there and many other
areas but um yeah i what they would do
is take from me they talked about all
these great ideals
but it was basically like those were
good ideas to expect of me
in infinity but never
provide back to me like we weren't
equals and
that so i'm i'm actually very scared of
that like i'm triggered when i run into
that because yeah i want to create this
world we're all talking about so i'm
drawn into these groups because i hear
this positive ideas i believe in
at least trying to get as close as
possible
but then i'm also now struggling with
feeling like those people that talk like
that are the most dangerous people i
have ever met so i i know that's not an
absolute and always true but um
yeah so it's really trying to explore
what your thoughts were i think you had
mentioned about
the community that you were in once and
i think you mentioned a similar dynamic
um and i yeah i just don't know how to
really navigate that or get out of that
trap
or is there a filter you do
i don't i don't know
i mean i really do just try to be a
hundred percent
sovereign without it dealing with
self-sufficiency
be like okay what can i do here what can
i learn
um there is a uncomfortableness
with the more evolved i get the more the
world
expects of me and the least it looks at
me like
it's the irony of like okay well if you
are capable of that right if you're
capable of looking after somebody's
needs before they've ever spoken them
then they expect that of you which means
that then and they're not giving it back
to you
it's like everything's on your shoulders
and you're given no respect for it right
because you're not seen as
as being in a position of authority or a
position
of being a better human being you're
just capable of that you're expected to
give it and that's your your normal so
like i couldn't possibly give that back
to you
it's like oh and the the like it comes
up a lot in the neurodiversity space
of people like expecting autistic people
to ask and expecting autistic people to
change their mindset and doing all and
i'm like wait a minute
if our autism stop keeps us very rigid
and stops us from doing those things
but your neurotypical brain doesn't why
aren't you changing
why aren't you the one who changes yeah
it's gonna be easier
yeah it's supposed to be easier for you
and yet that's never gonna happen
like it's all not like frankly the
neurotypical people can't handle that
they could like
they're so used to life working for them
that they can't handle changing
it becomes depression to have to be
equal or given equal burden you know
as you hear in and i guess most commonly
now in the racial debate right you know
for a white person that's never had to
consider or change how they do things
to and think of take a burden of
thinking of somebody else's different
experience
um equality feels like oppression right
so i think it's the same dynamic so
yeah i definitely yeah
at least in my experience even deeper
than that that the people we
hold in positions of privilege
are the exact opposite of what we see
them to be like i did this youtube video
a few months
it might have been six months ago at
this point called um like i was talking
about privilege and how i think that we
talk about it in a very weird way where
it's like
you're you're a man bodhi so you better
give me some of that privilege right and
it's not transferable you can't actually
transfer it
and so it feels like we're all kind of
going around i'm not begging for
privilege
when you can't transfer it when really
it's like actually i think it's more
easy to see
like containers of trauma that we have
and everyone has their container of
trauma however big or small
yours is you're
it's full right doesn't matter if it's a
teacup or a pool yours is full you can't
take on any more
what else is so all the little like
white karen's whose biggest problem is
can i get my kid to soccer practice on
time
have their little tea cup of trauma and
you're asking them to take on all racism
all homophobia all ableism
they can't handle it whereas people with
a lot of trauma when we heal a little
bit we have room to take on all the
teacups full
yeah but that puts the position of like
superhero-ness on the people who are
disadvantaged but yeah
we chose to be in this world to kind of
have that like
we expect the people in power who are
frankly like
toddlers throwing tantrums and we're
like well why can't you parents why
can't you adults why because they can't
we we were the ones who put them in that
position because they looked like they
had their together
because they didn't think and they
thought they had it and we didn't look
at all the circumstances and whereas
everyone who's gone through a lot of
trauma and gone through a lot of life
experience
has more to give and yet people are
gonna accept it less
and it's this juxtaposition and irony
that like feeds into right you're never
gonna see me as a physician authority
and that's okay because
you're seeing the emperor without
clothes like you're seeing what that
cost us but they just keep wanting to
put new emperors like
try this outfit honor it's like no no no
no
the whole system is like that and it
makes me have more compassion though for
people the karen's
right to be like oh you're a child
you don't know how to deal with this you
have no clue and so
but it doesn't help them deal with me
right it doesn't help that like they are
still
in their position of authority and
they're still in their position of like
oh i know i know how you do that you
just spiritually bypass everyone like
just positive thoughts
all the time and you're like oh sweetie
no no no no
yeah yeah well no totally for sure and i
i definitely agree with you too that
um you know recognizing that
you know as much as certain things even
i've been through um
yeah it's allowed me to you know the
good side of it is luckily i was able to
for whatever reason find a way to grow
and learn with it
and you know i do have ability to see
and maybe appreciate
other people's point of view in ways
that you know that karen let's say
wouldn't because they've just never had
to think about it doesn't even exist to
them they've never had to learn
struggle to find a word called spiritual
bypassing to explain what they were
going through
so i respect that and i'm definitely
with you in terms of
showing the empathy although it's not
that i have not you know had my fun
making fun of karen's
but at the same time i would readily
admit that if i saw that
you know they were hurting and they're
struggling i'm not gonna keep attacking
them
but it gets very tough when you once our
i guess bucket kind of runs down it's
like okay i've gone
i've put a lot of effort in here to
understand you now i'm kind of putting
because a lot of times it seems very
easy for those people or
we become monsters very easy especially
let's say me doing
so my co-living thing i understand where
it comes from because i was doing a
business and it was in san francisco
where the assumption is and i've got a
tech background so right away i must be
one of because it's very common it
usually is true you know those tech bros
that have a bunch of money and i didn't
have to do much but show up with my
you know and hustle somehow for four
years
making no money so where did that come
you know what i mean so
i get it but then it's like
so i i know that i have a job to do to
try to
explain and understand where they're
coming from and try to inform people
but it yeah there's a point when it's
like hey at what point do i get to say
hey
at least it isn't right that you're not
trying to even consider you're not
trying to be fair to me it's okay if you
can't
understand um but you're coming at me
like you're absolutely certain
that i'm somebody that you deserve to
attack right now
because i've put my foot because really
what happens is you're so you've
probably
experienced this it's like you'll be
good and accommodating for so long and
then finally when you say no
this is enough to people that are used
to you always helping them they take it
almost as an attack
where for you it's just like literally
i'll die if i keep giving you more of
myself right
um so it's really difficult and then
you know when you're in a community
environment you know of course it
depends
i've learned a lot and i'm
re-strategizing for what i need to do
next time and just being smarter of who
i let in and when
um not trying to make anybody bad up
front but just realizing like i need
more people that understand what it's
like to you know i need somebody like
you probably on the team that can
there's all sorts of dynamics but
it does and okay and if i just go even
to the the reason i jumped in talking is
in these anarchy groups i definitely
have ran into some really great
reasonable people that
give me the pathway try to see where i'm
at and are actually people probably
working on the anarchist ideas
with a chance of actually creating a
future as opposed to many of these
people that
it's again it's not anarchy but it's i
think it's unfortunately a lot of
humanity you know whether they're a
capitalist or
who knows what they hang on to one
myopic point like you know there's like
pull yourself up by the bootstraps
mentality that isn't
necessarily bad like you know to be
accountable to be sovereign
but there are obvious limits like you
know and if you can't have a rational
discussion
to say these are the circumstances and
you know like let's
i don't know just lack of a better you
know some reason a wheelchair actually
let's go to something a little bit
just like a race you know if somebody's
always starting the race
five miles ahead of the other person and
the person that's five miles behind
always gets judged for being such a
loser for not winning against the other
person why don't you just work hard by
like sam or whoever
like we of course know that makes no
sense but you get into a lot of
different ideological spaces nobody will
consider
that it's all innately yeah so it's just
maybe okay so if i sort of paint that
but going back to the idea of
sovereignty i guess
i'm wondering am i miss trying to find
out where this line is
and i'm trying to check myself to make
sure i'm not being blind to something i
guess
because there is a point when i think
yes it's like no i should put my foot
down and say
you can't compare me against sam he
started five miles ahead of me
every time like this isn't a measurement
of my speed
maybe he's faster than me but the truth
is we just don't know
and quit judging me uh so
you know so there's you can paint that
line but then when it comes to
dynamics like sovereignty and just talk
in the game b space and you've seen some
of the
things i've struggled with just in
different dialogues
trying to understand or even from a
community perspective so let's say from
game b
not that we're gonna answer this right
now but you know eventually kind of
realizing hey
as a group of people and what we think
sovereignty is and what we think
is on all of us to take where is that
point when we as a community also want
to help hold a bar
that it's like hey you know what this
you know right now it's fine if you
don't know how to deal with it
but you need to accept that at least
there's something for you to figure out
in your end at least respect that
you know it's not all on body kind of
thing like you know he's coming from a
valid place too
so and
i think yeah so i don't know i don't
expect you to give me that perfect line
it's really circumstantial but
um i think as you know we've
you know even in our tacoma during that
time
um yeah it's always i want to get
i want to get righteous and be mad and
stand up for myself but it's like trying
to sit it's like hey like
what are my blind spots here so
how do you define because sometimes it
isn't okay
you can't just walk away like you know
the truth is we are
we're living the world together there's
you know at a point
other people's personal choices and
sovereignty
does impact another person you know and
it depends on so many
you know we do have there's always a
power dynamic and
at what point is it acceptable for me to
not
be like oh i have to figure this out i
have to be sovereign it's my feelings
and say no no you actually
i deserve it's okay for me to be pushing
on you now that
hey like you need to we need to work
together here and you need to use your
sovereignty to respect
that we both exist here or something i
don't know
and i think you can't that never like
that never
now that doesn't mean that there's never
positions for that right when we're
doing
meta learning magic or my omega group or
together
tech there's going to be tension and we
need to figure it out and we're
we're choosing to be a group right so
we're figuring it we'll figure that out
but there's a big difference between me
demanding that right like demanding
everyone who showed up to week one of
of mlm like no no you have to continue
for six weeks right that was the deal
but that doesn't mean that everyone's
going to continue for six weeks life
comes up stuff happens
i don't get to control anyone else i get
to control and i can't even control that
my emotions around it my thing around it
and it's real my world view is that
everything happens for a reason
because it's shown itself to me the
right
conversation at the right time at the
right and so i wouldn't put that on
anyone else
i wouldn't be like oh yeah your mom died
for a reason you know like just get over
it
but for me it felt because i could be
like okay
i mean when i look at them the two
circumstances that happen in the last
couple years for me
one with my neighbor one with my sister
right i'm
clearly not objective but looking at it
i'm like there's literally nothing i did
wrong here
with my sister there was a bunch of
previous stuff of like oh i let our
dynamic be this i let you know what i
mean but not
in this instance there's nothing i could
have done differently it was exactly
what's supposed to happen
for my learning to come out of it and
the one with my you know neighbor who
yelled at me and i'm like there's
nothing what would
not have feet not walk on the floor like
there's nothing i could have kind of
done
besides maybe you know not knew she was
like that and not go and talk to her at
that time period or that kind of thing
but that's hindsight but i didn't let
her get away with it i was
like to a point i was the one person was
like we need to deal with this with
conflict resolution we need to deal with
this through
process and the the community itself
kind of dealt with it horribly
but it's like right that's on the
community right like it's like if this
is how you want to let people treat each
other if you wanna
and yet i understand she's a homeowner
what do you do is she gonna be there and
be talk like
you won't want to create all that
conflict but sweeping it under the rug
creates
deeper and deeper conflict is anyone
living in an intention
and so it's like but for me i just got
my learning out of it i don't need her
to learn i don't need her to grow in
fact when she did it a second time and i
laughed at her unfortunately she was
like i don't like to be laughed at it
was like well
i really don't know what to do with
somebody who's in their 70s and asking
me to control my seven-year-old
when they can't control themselves like
i really don't know what to do with that
except
laugh and then you know she kept kind of
trying to come and i was like listen i'm
not dealing with your anymore like
i'm not playing this game i'm not gonna
be quiet when i'm staying there i'm
gonna you know be
considerate but i'm not gonna go out of
my way you've burnt that bridge
so it doesn't mean allowing people to
walk all over you but it also like
i kind of have pulled myself out of that
community not because of that but
because of
the pandemic incovid but having
um like i could have i could have left
or
i could have allowed her to get away
with her that everyone else was and
i was like no she's not allowed to talk
to me
and so she does not she's a narcissist
she does not like that boundary
and so and i can tell like i can see
that she's trying to figure out how to
how to weasel like
maneuver and like like i'm the the one
who should
who should have authority and yet she
can't control me and it's really really
bothering her and i can have sympathy
for that i'm like it must be really hard
to live your life like you are
sure yeah living in intentional
community going from one to another
you're
not really liked everyone's glad to see
you go
like that's a very different position
than just having you know
social anxiety where i think people
don't want me there and i think
you know i mean it's a very different
actual fact
but it's like it's still my learning i
mean i had um an example that's closer
to what happened with you in the game b
space
the other day one of the people in the
game b space um i really don't like his
his
his world saving idea like i think it's
just a crap crap idea every time i
encounter it
i try like and he's someone who can't
jump on a conversation
so and he he holds it with like this
like i'm like
i don't want to be known for my id i
don't want to be famous i don't want to
and i'm like you can't
what it's probably yeah it's kind of
okay and
it like it's it's i've i've gotten in a
few one of the
previous people who was in game b end up
getting kicked out we had this conflict
i remember it was around and
i was like no i'm right you're wrong i
took this university he was he was like
a decade at least younger than me
and it turns out i didn't know that
there was this whole other part of game
theory that's based on cooperative games
because they only came out the last ten
years and so he introduced me to that i
was like oh cool
um and which i was glad for a conflict
but there was a lot of times where i was
putting in not emotional labor but
intellectual labor right and like
explaining
a resource-based economy and explaining
these things and the person just doesn't
want to understand or they can't
understand
it's not really on me to pick between
those two it's like okay
you don't have to but like you know
let's say for me it's like okay if they
are being good faith and it's like
i don't want to because yeah you know to
walk away from somebody especially if
they're trying to understand
you know of course there's times we
maybe have to make that choice but i
at least am very resonant to to want to
make i don't want to abandon somebody
so that sets me up for a dynamic where i
can you know if somebody is being
frankly a piece of like that is a
really
difficult dynamic and you can get abused
pretty easily in that
um so
yeah but i don't i don't like this with
this but anyway so this person posted
something along the lines of somebody
encountered my idea and they were
negative towards it
let's hash it out here on their facebook
page or something along those lines i
put like rhetorical questions
what i ask about my projects which is
like do i need people to be on board for
it right
and how many people do i need is it a
percentage out of a hundred no
actually i need five people to start mlm
to you know what i mean like it's
actually
i but that's because from being in that
tension of like oh god
i need ten thousand people how are ten
thousand people supposed to get along
that there's anyway so i just kind of
gave him some return which
for me were rhetorical we're like you
know do you need people to
like how many people do you need out of
100 people who hear your idea how many
are supportive do you need that to be a
specific percentage or do you need a
certain percentage of like a number of
people to be involved
and he answered them in a way that was
like well you didn't listen last time we
had this conversation and he put in a
lot of work and there was a lot and i
was like
those are rhetorical questions like it
was
like because he was like well do you ask
those about yours i was like yeah that's
why i'm offering them to you like these
are the things i ask
they want to like poke holes in it
because he knows i don't support his
idea
um and so but he anyway so then
it was just he posted stuff that he
always post stuff from like three years
ago like and i'm like okay but i didn't
know you three years ago so clearly it
hasn't evolved since
since i encountered it and it's based on
economics and on
and changing prices based on how much
you make per hour
and i'm like the economics doesn't make
sense he's like but amazon prime gives a
discount i'm like
yeah but they don't charge rich people
more and they also are losing on all of
that and
who like posted this point and i'm like
your demand curve i'm like there's no
demand there's no supply curve only a
demand curve he's like no you didn't
read
the demand curve is flat and i was like
oh sorry the supply i was like supply
curve can't be flat like literally and
then he posted this other thing which is
really informative of like
how you actually can do the entire area
under the curve for the
for the demand curve but it was like
based on monopoly based on this and a
flat demand curve is the
supply curve is the exact opposite and
i'm like okay do i continue
do i point this out to him no because
he's not going to hear it for me
he really don't mean i'm like listen i
understand economics you don't
but maybe maybe he does and it's a
deeper but like watching the thing he
sent me i was like do you not see
that you're simultaneously needing this
to be a monopoly and a perfectly
competitive system this is perfectly
competitive
this is a monopoly you don't get a
choice in any of it and that whenever
you change the price people are just
gonna go choose somewhere else
yet he's so dog with a bone like this is
the solution he puts so much time and so
much energy into it and i'm like
use your time and energy anywhere else
this project is broken
well just the same type of life like
it's like i had the biggest
inauguration in history it's like uh
everybody has pictures
but like you know those things are just
like oh like
but so yeah it's it's tough i guess
i wonder if like i think where i
and again why i thought of talking to
you about this
first was really
because i guess yeah like i can always
walk away from things
or we all can right you know that's the
sovereignty idea but at a point
but then there's a flip side of that
even to myself it's like well am i just
quitting and walking away
versus should i be trying to find a way
to work with the community because like
in my mind i'm like no this is a
reasonable point
where we should create a culture where
we expect the other person to have a
we put we don't do it in a negative way
like there's when somebody can't do
something and it's very clear like i
think that's
abuse to keep pushing at them and not
respect it and just walk away
but yeah so it's kind of i think when we
if we use that example and we talked a
little bit a month ago there
during that and part of my grind was
well no i feel like the community should
maybe
step up a little bit here like what's
our what can i expect what's a
reasonable expectation of each other
and whether or not it's in the game b
space really trying to decide for myself
well how do
i need to navigate these dynamics
because if i walk away and grab my ball
every time i don't like something that's
also not a solution
and it isn't fair to because that's a
cop out at a point right because then
you're telling everybody that they can
never fight for what they believe in
and well that wouldn't get us very far
either so of course there's
it's a balance of course but
that was yeah so that was where that's
where i get triggered on the sovereignty
idea because i feel like
i'm scared that it's going to become
this thing that's going to be used in
perpetuity to dismiss me and i can't
ever expect to be reasonably heard i
can't say
this person screaming at me it's
important that we all agree this wall is
white
this wall is white but this person won't
accept it like
i'm supposed to just leave now and we're
not going to deal with this and
solve the problem like those kind of
moments i suppose which is maybe
somewhat like what you're kind of you
know it depends what's at stake of
course
um maybe that's the question that i'm
ultimately hoping to get
do you even know what yeah suggestions
i would give are that i feel like you're
i
we all do this you're dealing with an
individual like it's the group
right that this i don't remember who the
person was so this is
right instead of one person in game b
now the difference is game
like i think you would see how wrong
that is if it was like a dating
relationship right where like somebody
cheated on you or like
oh women are horrible or all men are
horrible
yeah you can live in that but it's like
why are they why do they want me to hold
the door
for them and not hold the door open for
them because they're two different
people right they're not the same person
i don't think my problem with my
rationality on it i'm definitely not
projecting
everybody in game b is this and you know
the great thing about
the the group i the community i'd say
anyways that i'm gaining a lot from
is the fact that i know there's a lot of
different views in there that i
know very confidently that i do not
agree with but
learning their perspective and why you
know i think it is valuable and i'm okay
with that so
i am but even on but even for them i
guess
how do i put this i feel like the
sovereignty thing it just kind of
i think it's it's a very important core
concept it seems to be
and having some kind of cultural
expectation or some kind of
norm it's like at what point do we uh
step up because let's go back to the
anarchy thing too which contributes
because they're like oh we don't need
government we can just you know mutual
aid and we're all the
society will stand up and stand up for
the right thing and i'm like
okay but this is kind of the problem
then when you're
then talking to most anarchists and you
can't have a rational
dialogue either where it's like okay so
nothing's ever going to happen here
and your answer to everything is the
community will solve it but even in this
moment the community is not solving it
they're so you know which of course
i can't make anything but i have i'm
trying to determine
when do i give up on a community maybe
it's like when is it me and i've gotta
keep pushing on me or when it has the
sovereignty thing let's say
become a cop out for behavior
and nobody's owning their frankly
like yeah yeah and game b
is a weird group because like women
right that we're not a cohesive
um like women didn't get hurt
we're going to not cheat we're going to
have chairs pulled out for us or not
it's like i'm a woman and i have my own
thoughts and they align with
other women sometimes and don't align
with other women sometimes and i think
we can get that with women
but we ca even though we're going to
continually be like wait why are why
have you
all not democratically decided on what
how my actions should affect you oh my
how my choice should that game be is a
weird nebulous it's kind of because it's
not
an organization that started decided
rules this you know what i mean like
like it could have maybe and i don't
even think it should have because i
think that it is trying to be more
nebulous
like hey all we're here for is we're
trying to create an omni-win
anti-robbery
and find your own groups and yeah there
isn't
authority yeah i agree and i'm very
comfortable with those kind of dynamics
and frankly that's probably how i've
gotten
where i am um well at least my story of
life is that
i know these answers aren't nice and
easy and clean and
you know we definitely have some in that
group and you find them in all of them
that think they can just create this
nice structure and everything's clear
um so i definitely wouldn't
definitely at this stage would i even
want to suggest like here's the
rules but i feel like there's just
i guess if we look at game b as being
okay well this is what we're trying to
kind of aim towards like i do think that
all of us in there at least in our own
minds are going towards that
better for all of us kind of idea now
i'm sure a lot of those better for all
do not align
but it's still kind of the same essence
like there's something there that we're
aligned on
and i guess i feel like those ideas uh
being accountable each other there's
loosely some like there's a point when
it seems absurd
for it not to be like hey guys like
we've got and i get maybe kind of
triggered
on that some of these rules like it is
an absolute line in the sand it's like
okay well
because like to me at a point i i agree
like ad hominem attacks attacking the
person
is not where you want to start to be on
the ideas but at the end of the day
there's a there's a time when the person
is the problem
or being the problem it doesn't mean you
need to define them
but it's like okay like when do i say
hey group
are we serious like should i be hanging
out with you guys
like what is this and no this isn't just
me it's my sovereignty i should walk
away again it's like no i've done enough
so yeah so there's a few that like
sometimes you are arguing about whether
the sky is blue right and it's you
want to dig your feet in and do it more
and yet there's no point to that it
either is or isn't and the other persons
are going to see it or not see it
and so the group being like okay the
sky's blue no one can say anything
else it's like well that's maybe helping
because we don't have to talk about that
one but most of the time we're arguing
one person thinks they're arguing the
sky is blue and another person's arguing
yeah but what about sunrise and
you know what i mean like you're both
right but you're not going to see from
the other
resistance position point of view and so
my my suggestion would be like what
happened with your conversation with
whatever his name is because we don't
remember
and actually your example even right now
like i will readily admit that it is
more what you were just talking about
like i
i had a hard time accepting because to
me and i'm pretty sure i could
you know illustrate that if anybody at
the time including me to actually go
through
you know step by step pointed out you
know i was putting myself in their shoe
and showing
some kind of acknowledgement of where
they're coming from but like no this is
it
and they weren't doing that so that's
what triggered me but i think that
you're also
right in hindsight they just weren't
able to grasp that it's not and i know
that there's people like that
and so then yeah so you know mostly in
this that case actually i agree it was a
me thing to grow and learn to sit with
it so that's
fine but it you know there was a lot of
it's aggregated
you know who knows there's stuff going
on in my life but then it's not like all
of us so
but yeah it still brings up that that
question of
hey when i guess it's a level of wanting
to have confidence if you invest with
any group of people
um like i'm asking myself like am i
being smart at times and i'm not
currently wrestling with that but it's
like
have i just gone into a group of people
where it's like i think i should be able
to expect this
of each other they should be expected of
me
and yeah like you know that was kind of
i think that's the thing that i
get cycled on maybe we all do but
yeah i think it's just i don't even yeah
there's not really an answer to this
it's like
i think it's an important discussion
because if like a bunch of individuals
in game b
right or attacking someone or doing
something that's very different than one
on one
like where it is then it is kind of game
b that's doing it even though it's still
not it's five individuals in game b
not necessarily that kind of like as an
individual with sovereignty
who has decided to walk away there's
three options to walk away from right
you can walk away from that conversation
you can walk away from that individual
or you can walk away from the group
entirely
and it depends on your relationship with
the individual it depends on your
relationship with the group
right that like yes you can outside and
be like i'm walking away and i'm not
gonna
not gonna have this conversation or walk
like we could get in a fight during this
i've literally never but like
you know what i needed like that we're
never talking again or does that mean
that we have a conversation later to
to deal with it right so you can walk
this is too heated i'm leaving
i'm gonna kill my sovereignty yeah or
i'm never dealing with jubilee again she
doesn't know how to do omega rules she
doesn't hold her own sovereignty
i don't hold my sovereignty when she's
not holding hers i'm walking away from
her
or you're walking away from your
organization i'm in right like
like which would make sense if it was if
it was mlm right because it's like mine
is coming through me
versus game b which isn't mine but i'm
in it
right so yeah which one are you
and which one are you making it mean
right does jubilee equal game b and
therefore it was everyone
or that that kind of thing and so i just
go with what can i learn out of it
and where can i find my sovereignty and
i found it's helped me evolve
drastically but the world doesn't look
at it like i evolved if anything they
look at it like i default and so i'm
like
here i am in my with all the naked
emperors and you guys are just like
but that's what i signed up for in this
pla on this in this lifetime
is to have that position yeah i know for
sure like ultimately of course yeah
it comes down you got it you can only
make your own choices and unfortunately
you know sometimes that may turn out
that oh you're just screwed and
your only choice in life is to be
screwed um
so so yeah like i yeah it really depends
i guess i know if just to put it like a
stark contrast maybe just you know
leaving it in the spot is because i
think
most people would accept this like in
reality
there's a point when it becomes let's
just say you know sexism and you know
um so women that are just if you walked
into a room and a bunch of guys
harassing you and it was one guy but the
rest of us are sitting around
but we just let it happen right and it's
you walking away though especially if
that's
say let's say let's not even call it
just you know that's the world
you can't just walk away from the
economy the world and survive you
there's a point when expecting you to
use your sovereignty and walk away
is expecting you to sacrifice your life
so that we can chill
and yeah so that's an extreme start but
it's
yeah it's kind of because i would say i
think a good
a good like if i walk into a room with a
bunch of guys and one guy's
you know making rape jokes at me about
me i think that would be very clear and
i would yeah i would disown the rest of
the men for not doing i'd be like i'm
walking away from all of you
but if i walk into a room and one guy's
like hey why don't you smile you'd look
so much prettier if you smile
now that's clearly sexism and that's
clearly but like it's not
the men might not know that right the
men might be like i just asked her to
smile like it's not their same world
view and so i could i
i could experience i should know that by
now like if they're listening to
anything but yeah i guess
by now yeah for sure but like that's
because of your world view that you've
seen right exactly
once you encounter something enough
times you're like how has everyone not
encountered this but it's like the way
the universe works
that you encounter the same thing over
and over again yeah like i'm just
down to the amount of times i go into a
restaurant in vancouver and i'm like do
you guys have fair trade coffee and
they're like what's fair trade coffee
oh really what you're part of vancouver
are you getting
working in coffee and you don't know
what fair trade coffees but they don't
they've never encountered it like
it's not gonna help to be like you idiot
how do you don't know what you gotta
remember too we're like 20 years older
than some of these new people
it's like oh yeah that's right you guys
weren't even born when yeah
exactly right yeah no it's yeah it's
yeah it's so yeah interesting i guess
it's
it is a dialogue just i think maybe
important to always have because
because the truth is let's just say in
one of those examples say you did walk
away but then you were going to starve
and you have a kid and they wouldn't be
able to eat like because there wasn't
options available you know then it's
like you really can't
and yeah so it gets to the extreme and i
guess if i was just to put
my kind of at least the moment that time
we were talking in
it's not that it's game b or anybody
owes this to me um
but in my mind i'm taking or and always
have been
i really give myself what i'm going on
is like i really want to invest and make
x happen
so you know me coming to the game space
is a lot of okay i'm
really going to direct my energy this is
my life
you know really i'm going here and i see
a lot of good things but then it's like
you know part of me is almost i'm
pushing because i'm wanting to see like
am i going to break this
or is it going to prove to me that this
is where i should stay and maybe that's
exactly what you have
to do you know it's individual choice
but that would definitely have a spoke
to at least that moment of what i was
feeling was that frustration is like you
guys are hanging this big you know
you're doing your
like you're gonna do your marketing
level scam like buy these sharpest
knives
ever like your grandma will love you and
it's like i want my grandma to love me
and i'm chasing this thing and then then
you start to feel like wait am i being
lied to you am i being
promised something that's only meant
like you know i guess if we go into
privileged ideas it's like oh like i
think again you know
growing you in alberta it's like yeah
working hard works great for these kinds
of people
um but not me because there's things
about me that will never
no matter what i do um get me through
there and of course that's a very
like well i guess that's like the
gaslighting so in a way so
anyways that's kind of
the thing i spin around i suppose or
that drove this conversation so
and crazy anarchist
anyways um yeah i don't know you have
anything else you want to say or
do we leave it in a we had a
conversation and yeah there's no answer
well there's never there's never an
answer buddy i'm just i was just
someone just texted me back one of the
people in omega group left
she's like i need to take care of myself
that she hasn't been there in a few
months and she finally was like i'm
gonna take um until the new year i'm not
gonna come so that i know that i don't
have to tell you
my sixth group no no it's not that my
omega group is one i've been
talking to for um a year it has eric
from liberate mankind
the other person who's in it that he
isn't six by six is in my girl okay
and we've been um talking for a year and
there's five of us that
regularly show up except one he hasn't
for the last one anyway
she was like i'm not gonna come back and
we have this this joke of like a god
that's not a god which is like the
universe and the kismet and stuff that
that happens and just the random
and i'm like i don't like your god who's
not a god like but
like it's like it's not deciding on
things that i wanted to decide on like
how dare your god tell you not to come
to our group when my god told me that
yours should come to my group
i'm like wait are they the same god can
i be blasphemous can i like it's like
for like
god's lying to you maybe maybe it is and
they're playing you guys
but it's like the fact that she didn't
show up or that she said yeah i'm not
coming
gave me the opportunity to learn that
right as much as i'm in the no i don't
like your god who's not a god and i'm
gonna sit with that because i'm kind of
okay not liking yours are they the same
one as mine and i argue with mine but i
can't argue
with yours i can't argue with how you
came to your conclusion because it's not
based on logic
or emotion it's based on like i just
don't feel that i this is the thing i
can lose
but it's like it's exactly what was
supposed to happen so i can get that
understanding whatever's going to come
out of it
and going from that place she's not
wrong for not attending and i'm not
wrong for feeling like you're god's
wrong
we're telling you not to it's where we
both are
and there'll be something that comes
from it totally totally
no yeah i think i get you i get you for
sure cool
well this was good to to talk through
and hopefully
somebody someday if they ever watch this
this was useful for them too so
um yeah definitely i'm just curious when
you're that
uh omega group is that a game b group or
is that totally separate
even if it's interesting through game b
yeah a year ago eric
contacted me saying hey is there any
wood let's have this omega group
let's practice i want to practice omega
rule i want to make a rule let's do it
and so we both invited different people
and over the course so i'd say a month
we ended up um
some people fell away and some people
came and i'd say for the last year we've
had a rather
the five of us that made rather
regularly yeah that'd be a that's
another it
ties into the same type of discussion
because i think i've even talked to you
about it that rule omega is like well
at one point it's like this person's
clearly not good faith so screw that
you know it's like because again it's a
trap the
the best good faith person is always at
a disadvantage because
somebody that's definitely not they'll
never admit it and then you're screwed
so yeah and there's a very big
difference also
about um typing out a conversation
and having a conversation on video which
is why i had suggested did you guys end
up getting on a video chat you and the
other
no but well you know i won't draw
conclusions on this person i'm not
surprised but i offered it and i
never heard back from them again i don't
think they were very interested in
learning which
to me makes sense based on the way the
engagement was going like
i'm pretty sure there's a level of
obtuseness whether it was fully
conscious
it's a certain mentality and i think
yeah you know you recognize it when you
see it so
but anyways it's fine and i felt you
know that's the kind of person i want to
be
so and i also agree because uh the way i
can
without i'm pretty blunt generally it's
on a text there's just so
i by default just always assume things
are sarcastic in a funny happy way but
then there's also people that think that
sarcasm can only be bad
so then i'm only bad where
that can happen when people are seeing
me too but at least
i think like you know yeah seeing the
whole you know me
it's uh yeah least less likely to go bad
so i agree with you um so i think that's
good
and that's something i'm trying to get
better at because it's so
especially i know what i'm like i get
triggered like ah i'm just going to spit
out what i'm thinking but it's
usually not a very good idea so
anyways cool well thanks for uh yeah
meeting with me what time was it there
noon no no 10 a.m it was 9am my time we
started no it's almost 10 a.m all right
we can say goodbye to youtube i will
stop the recording bye youtube